本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 白bye JoJo108 Nothing Danky blfoxcon
校对： 小妖怪   后期： Pilar
彼岸是天堂 第二季 第六集
艾德蒙・洛维特
在干什么 叔叔?
What are you doing, Uncle?
用你自己的名字当店名 不是个简单的事
To have your name above a shop, it's no small thing.
你才发现么?
Have you only just noticed?
你忘了 是么?
You've forgotten, haven't you?
明显 我知道或者应该知道你在说什么
Clearly I have or I'd know what you're talking about.
五年了
Five years.
到这周
This week.
那块招牌挂上去有五年了
Five years since that sign went up,
天堂百货取代了艾默森服装店
this place stopped being Emmerson's Drapery and became The Paradise.
芙罗拉?
Flora?
你在哪 亲爱的?
Where are you, darling?
芙罗拉?
Flora?
- 芙罗拉? - 嘘
- Flora? - Ssh.
芙罗拉?
Flora?
约翰?
John?
被你发现了
You caught me.
对不起 亲爱的 我没能忍住
I'm sorry, sweetheart. I couldn't resist.
我总是在想坐在这里是什么感觉
I've always wondered what it would feel like to sit there.
也许我该当心自己的位子啦
Perhaps I ought to be careful where I leave my trousers lying.
我们玩个游戏
It's a game.
不管凯瑟琳说什么 我们都别和她说话
Whatever Katherine says, we don't speak to her.
老天啊! 搞什么鬼
Heavens! What a trick.
我差不多找了你一整天了
I might have been searching for you the whole day.
我都急疯了
It has quite jangled my nerves.
汤姆 亲爱的 听到了么?
Tom, darling, did you hear me?
芙罗拉...
Flora...
- 我们去树迷宫里玩好吗? - 好的爸爸
- Shall we go and play in the maze? - Yes, Papa.
汤姆
Tom.
芙罗拉
Flora.
我在和你说话
I'm talking to you.
芙罗拉宝贝 你追我还是我追你?
Flora, sweetheart, will you chase me or shall I chase you?
你来追我 爸爸
You chase after me, Papa.
你们今天当我不存在么?
Do I not exist today?
你们倒是说句话啊!
I demand that you speak to me!
汤姆 你已经这样好几天了
Tom, you have been like this for days.
像鬼一样盯着我 又一句话也不说
Like a ghost staring at me but, but saying nothing.
到底怎么了?
What is the matter?
女士
Ma'am.
- 早上好 - 先生
- Good morning. - Sir.
我们当然得好好庆祝这个日子
Of course we must mark the occasion.
橱窗展览 布满彩旗
Window displays, flags and bunting throughout the place.
装饰一新
All manner of decorations.
要不 在天花板上悬挂天堂鸟
I thought, perhaps, birds of paradise hung from the ceiling.
达德利 我很欣赏你的干劲十足
I appreciate the sentiment, Dudley,
但这是我们陶醉于做这些琐事的时候么?
but are these times for us to revel in our position?
先生 早上好
Sir. Morning.
每个可人的小玩意
Every bright bauble
都将是汤姆・威斯顿的眼中钉肉中刺
will be a poke in the eye of Tom Weston.
一想到他会看到我们的成就 我就开心
I like the thought of him seeing what we have achieved here.
也对
Yes.
- 那就做吧 - 莫里先生
- Then let's do it. - Mr Moray
早上好
- Morning.
Good morning.
简直跟泡在了蜜罐里似的 这感觉太美了!
I feel like I'm wrapped in butter, It's heavenly!
美吗?
Is it heavenly?
我是说 我穿起来很蠢么? 我该买么?
I mean, do I look foolish in it? Should I buy it?
这... 这很完美 夫人 我觉得
It... it's perfect, ma'am, I think.
或者... 你觉得如何 克莱拉?
Perhaps... What do you think, Clara?
夫人我向你保证
Ma'am I promise you,
这条裙子 是最优雅时尚的选择
it is a most tasteful and fashionable choice.
我该什么时候穿? 有的裙子是晚...
When do I wear it? I know some dresses are for evening...
夫人 这件裙子任何时候都能穿
Ma'am, this dress can be worn at any time.
噢 这太好玩了 你们又这么热心地帮我
Oh, but this is such fun and you're so kind to help me.
穿这裙子要配什么鞋子好?
What shoes does a lass wear with this dress?
你喜欢什么款式 夫人?
What kind of shoes would you prefer, madam?
我想要你来帮我选
I'd prefer you to choose.
你之前给我选的这些 简直是...
Everything you've chosen so far, it's just...
完美
Perfect.
不如...
What about...
这款灰色纽扣中靴?
The grey button boots?
要来一双试试么?
Would you like to try a pair?
要是你能帮我包起来 我丈夫就会来付款
If you can have them wrapped up, my husband will come in to pay.
当然 巴伦坦夫人
Of course, Mrs Ballentine.
我亲爱的巴伦坦 他把我捧在手心里爱着
Darling Ballentine. He does love to spoil me.
这也不多 是么?
It's not too much, is it?
买这么多会不会很俗很不淑女呢?
It's not coarse and unladylike to buy so much?
才不会 夫人 我们会帮你打包好
Not at all, Madam. We will have it all ready for you.
我以前是个护士
I was a nurse, you know,
我有的差不多就一双靴子 你看我现在
with hardly a pair of boots to my name. Look at me now.
不知是谁梦寐以求的呢?
Who would have dreamed?
我从没想过我能每天穿着这么精美的制服上班
I never dreamed I'd have such a fine uniform to wear every day
还和这么好的朋友们住在一起
and such fond friends to share a dorm with.
包裹谁来送呢?
Who will deliver the parcels?
- 会有送货员的 夫人 用送货车 - 噢
- Oh, the delivery lads deliver, ma'am, on their delivery wagon. - Oh.
我更希望是你来送 苏西
I was rather hoping it would be you, Susy.
或者你 克莱拉
Or you, Clara.
我就能把它们都试一遍
then I could try them all on and
然后你就能告诉我...
you could tell me...
你还能看看我们家的枝形吊灯
And you could see our chandeliers
感觉一下地毯有多厚
and feel how thick the carpets are.
巴伦坦夫人 如果您能抽出一上午在家试衣
If you would care for a morning fitting at home,
我可以来安排
Mrs , I'm sure that could be arranged.
可以
Yes.
我喜欢试衣这个词 我们可以喝茶吃烤饼
I like the sound of a fitting. We could have tea and scones.
还是说 烤饼只能午后吃?
Or, perhaps scones are only eaten in the afternoon?
请原谅 夫人 我的意思是午后试衣
Forgive me, ma'am. What I meant to say was an afternoon fitting.
好的!
Yes!
艾德蒙叔叔
Uncle Edmund,
这是我这周第三次在旅馆看到你了
this is the third time I've seen you at the inn this week.
奥德丽难道不会想你吗?
Won't Audrey be missing you?
别急 德妮丝
Don't fret, our Denise.
天知道 我已经让人捎去便条
Hell's teeth, I've sent her a note
告诉她我在回家的路上了
telling her I'm on my way back home.
我决不会干涉别人的家事
Far be it for me to interfere in another man's marriage,
但你为什么不自己去送便条给她?
but why didn't you just take her the note yourself?
对啊
Yes.
那你这会儿就能在家了
Then you would have been there,
就用不着送便条去解释为什么你...不在家
you wouldn't have needed to send a note to say why you're... not there.
坐吧 苏西 让你的小脑袋瓜儿歇歇
Have a sit down, Susy. Rest your mind a while.
你得承认 洛维特先生 你没有理由留这儿
You must admit, Mr. Lovett, you don't have any cause to stay...
我有
Yes, I do.
我不是干涉别人婚姻上的私事的人 但是
I'm not one to meddle in the affairs of a marital nature, but,
你的理由是什么 艾德蒙?
what are your reasons, Edmund?
我不能因为这小店看起来破烂不堪就卖了它
I can't sell the shop because it looks so worn down and decrepit.
要是我粉刷一下 你就瞧着吧
Now, if I paint it up, you'll see,
它会成为一个小小的购物胜地
it'll make it a more agreeable proposition for any buyer.
辛苦劳作个几天 一切都会天差地别
A few days sweat and toil will make all the difference.
你当刮目相看
You'll see.
- 加油 艾德蒙! - 我会证明给你们看
- Come on, Edmund! - I'll prove to the lot of you,
我在这儿唯一的理由是我打算出发了!
I'm only here because I intend to leave!
啊呦 艾德蒙!
Ah, Edmund!
她做到了 不是吗?
She's done it, hasn't she?
巴伦坦夫人
Mrs Balentine.
她得到了我们大家梦寐以求的一切
She's got what we all hanker after.
她嫁的是多金的丈夫 过的是奢华的生活
She's bagged herself a wealthy husband, living the grand life.
我不想 我想要温柔体贴的丈夫
I don't. I want a kind husband.
苏西 再考虑一下
Susy, think on.
如果他不富裕的话 温柔体贴有何意义呢?
If he's not well-off, what good is his kindness?
我们都说梦想得到爱情
We all say what we dream of is love,
但是 我们就承认吧
but, let's admit it,
我们真想要的是财富与爱情兼具
what we really want is love and riches.
每一个踏过那扇门的光鲜亮丽的女人
Every fine-dressed woman who walks through that door,
就是我们艳羡的
we just long for what she has.
这就是我们来百货商店工作的原因
That's why we come to work in a department store.
你都不发言 德妮丝
You're quiet, Denise.
你怎么看巴伦坦夫人的好运?
What do you say about Mrs Ballentine's good fortune?
我不会嫉妒我们的顾客
I don't envy our customers.
我也不渴望到天堂百货来购物挥霍
I can't say I long to come to The Paradise to shop and to spend.
噢 我们走吧
Oh, here we go.
你渴望什么 德妮丝?
What do you want, Denise?
在我梦想中的世界
I dream of a world
女人不需要嫁一个富有的丈夫
where a woman doesn't need a rich husband.
噢 是啊
Oh, yes.
我还期待有一天女人当选首相
And I'm looking forward to the day when a woman is Prime Minister,
女人成为布道坛上的牧师
and a woman is a priest in the pulpit
女人掌控天堂百货!
and a woman is in charge of The Paradise!
汤姆?
Tom?
他建议送德妮丝去巴黎...
His proposal to send Denise to Paris...
我怀疑他这么做是为了和我作对
I have little doubt he did it to antagonise me.
他擅自从店里拿走了你父亲的表
He took your father's watch from the store
甚至没经过你的同意
without so much as a by-your-leave.
就好像他知道我们谈了什么
It was as if he knew what you and I had spoken about,
你父亲的意愿是...
your father's wishes for the watch...
..把这只表留给你的丈夫
..to be left to the man you married.
怎么了?
What is it?
你明天能来吗?
Will you come back tomorrow?
我们到时候再说
We can speak then.
当然
Of course.
求你了 告诉我
Please, tell me.
天哪 帮帮我
God, help me.
天哪 请帮帮我吧
God, please help me.
他竟然能这么残酷
He is capable of such cruelty.
我从来没想到!
I never imagined!
我们结婚结的太匆忙 我几乎不了解他
We married in such haste. I hardly knew him.
我一直怕惹到他 生活在恐惧中
I live in terror of upsetting him.
我不知道他会如何反应所以一直不敢说出来
I dare not speak for fear of how he will react.
我总感觉他恨我
There are times I think he hates me.
他一心想要惩罚我
He wishes only to punish me.
这种日子我一天也受不了了!
I cannot bear one more day!
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你不能这么过下去 凯瑟琳
You cannot live like this, Katherine.
那我又能怎样?
What else can I do?
答应我 如果你需要人陪一定要来找我
Promise me you will come to me when you need someone.
是她 是巴伦坦夫人! 她和她丈夫一起来了
It's her. It's Mrs Ballentine! She's here with her husband.
他 他是 他不是...
And he's, well, he's, well he's not...
我想说的是 他不是...
What I'm trying to say is, he's not...
她们在这 亲爱的!
Here they are, my darling!
我的新朋友们
My new friends.
- 她们一直都很照顾我 - 谢谢 姑娘们
- They've been looking after me so sweetly. - Thank you, girls,
让我妻子成为这整个城市最幸福的女人
for making my wife the happiest woman in the whole city.
拿出来 巴伦坦
Well, show them, Ballentine.
让她们看看我们有多感激
Show them how obliged we are.
哦 没错!
Oh, yes!
我带您去收银台吧  巴伦坦先生
Perhaps you might come with me to the Cashier desk, mr Ballentine,
去那儿结账
to settle your account?
我打赌它一定在最下面!
I'll wager it's down all those stairs!
我可是刚刚爬上来! 谢谢 亲爱的!
And I've just climbed up them! Thank you, dear!
这边请
This way.
我想让你们给我给我示范下
I need you to show me
穿上我的新衣服应该如何走路
how to walk in my new dresses.
我知道你在想什么 你在想
I know what you're thinking. You're thinking,
"这个男人
"Here's a man who's
深爱着他的妻子
"so in love with his wife
所以他会放任她所有心血来潮的行动"
that he will indulge her every whim."
你们的业绩要大大地上升咯!
Oh, how your sales will soar!
莫里先生 我能为你介绍巴伦坦先生吗?
Mr Moray, sir, might I introduce you to Mr Ballentine?
坎贝尔・巴伦坦? 我们之前见过一面 先生
Campbell Ballentine? We met once before, sir.
我想是在赌马赛场上
I believe it was at the race course.
哦 是的 没错!
Oh, yes, of course!
我那天运气可不怎么样!
I lost a fortune that day!
我很高兴能在我的... 在天堂百货见到您
Well, I am pleased to see you in my...in The Paradise.
失陪一下 先生
If you'll excuse me, sir?
这边
This way.
巴伦坦先生的账 谢谢
Mr Ballentine's accounts, please.
多么辉煌的企业!
What a splendid enterprise!
我们最近开了一家美食厅
We've recently opened a Food Hall.
我们的东洋式房间大受欢迎
We have an Oriental Room which has proved very popular.
我们打算进一些不同价位的商品
We try to stock items at a range of prices
来吸引各层次的顾客
to attract all manner of customers.
那些无法负担贵重商品的人
Those who can't afford the finer goods
仍可以进来观看它们
can still come in to gaze at them.
我们还有童装店
We have a Childrenswear department
床上用品 男装和家具 我们一直在努力扩大
Bedding, Menswear and Furniture. We're always looking to expand.
我有一个酒厂
I have a brewery.
从一瓶麦芽酒开始做起 到现在
I started out with one ale, and now,
我为这个城市超过一半的酒馆和旅店提供酒水
I supply more than half the inns and hostelries of the city.
除了这些
And beyond.
我或许应该歇歇了 但我仍然每天坚持工作
I may get short of breath, but I still go to work every day,
我仍然知道我每个供应商都姓什么
and I still know each employee by their first name.
我也知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
应该在我们的美食厅提供您的酒
We ought to supply those ales of yours in our Food Hall!
感觉就像是... 就好像你的脚踩在轮子上
The idea...is to walk as though your feet were on wheels.
噢 像这样吗?
Oh. Like this?
不要一上一下的 手别动
Not up and down, no hands.
我们叫它"游步"... 苏西?
Er, "tripping", we call it...Susy?
非常好!
Wonderful!
把你的手放在前面 像这样 然后...
Place your hands in front, like this. And...
苏西?
Susy?
女人不要迈大步
Long strides are not feminine.
小步走 好吗?
Short strides. Yes?
小...步走
Short...strides.
每一步都要用你的优雅和平稳
Every step is meant to draw attention for
来吸引人们的注意
its grace and poise.
我不确定能有这种优雅和平稳!
I'm not sure I can do grace and poise!
那先走平稳了再考虑优雅吧
Perhaps try poise and worry about grace later.
我们一定要一起出去
We must all go out together.
我请客 我们该去哪?
Be my treat. Where shall we go?
我们能参加的最盛大的晚会是什么?
What's the most lavish night out we could possibly have?
巴伦坦夫人...
Er, Mrs Ballentine...
拜托 叫我露西尔...
Please, call me Lucille...
露西尔 不用这么破费
Lucille, there's no need for extravagance.
巴伦坦真英俊 不是吗?
Ballentine's so handsome, isn't he?
你丈夫一定很爱你 夫人
Your husband clearly adores you, madam.
他有时也很风趣
He can be so funny sometimes.
我找不到比他更好的人了
I've never known a kinder man.
我想邀请你们都来我家里
I'm going to invite you all out to the house,
那一定是今年最快乐的聚会
and it will be the jolliest party of the year.
求你了 快说你会来!
Please, say you'll come!
哦 我们很乐意去
Oh, we'd love to come.
我们还想参观下你家的吊灯呢
We want to look at your chandeliers.
不是吗 克莱拉?
Don't we, Clara?
或者 有时我们周末会去野餐
Or, sometimes we have a picnic on Sundays.
我真高兴能认识你们
I am so glad I found you.
我最近见过的女人都是那种出身高贵
The only women I've met so far have been those well-to-do society wives
又瞧不起我的人
who look down their noses at me.
我喜欢野餐 来我家的花园一起坐坐
I love picnics. Come and sit in my garden.
我们一起喝香槟
We'll have champagne
还有烤肉和果汁...
and roasted meats and oranges...
我们都... 很愿意去 露西尔
We would all...love to come, Lucille.
我能请您喝杯白兰地吗 先生?
Can I offer you a glass of brandy, sir?
我一定要除掉他
I must be rid of him.
也许我们应该进里面谈 先生
Perhaps we should speak inside, sir.
是的 当然
Yes. Yes of course.
我再也受不了他在这里作威作福了
I can't bear to watch him lord it about this place for one more day.
太匆忙可不太合适 威斯顿先生
Haste will not serve you well, Mr Weston.
如果您真下决心要除掉莫里先生
If you are determined to dispose of Mr Moray,
可不能顺了他的意
do not do so on his terms.
如果您现在解雇他 反而对他有利
If you dismiss him now, you will play into his hands.
- 他可能会翻身的 - 你什么意思?
- He would come out on top. - What do you mean?
我听说了一些事 先生
There are things I have heard, sir.
您会不会相信 这件事我知道得最清楚?
Will you trust that I know best in this?
让我来做些安排
Let me make some arrangements
我会把如何终结莫里的提案摆在您面前
and a proposal will be laid before you that will finish Moray.
五周年庆典! 我们会用丝带 彩旗和天堂鸟
A five-year celebration! We will deck the halls with ribbons, bunting
来装饰大厅给每一个顾客看
and a bird of paradise for every customer.
莫里先生 您的信
Mr Moray, sir, your messages.
达德利能处理这些事
Dudley can deal with these.
我只是借用它一下 不会偷走的
I'm only borrowing it, I'm not going to steal it!
我要用它来把活干完 不是吗?
I need it to get the job done, don't I?
好吧 下次最好找莫里先生或达德利先生
Well, next time ask Mr Moray or Mr Dudley,
或者任何比这梯子高的人
or someone else higher up the ladder.
看到这条街了吗?
You see this street?
我上上下下打量它
I look up and down it,
没有比我更早在这儿的人了
there's nobody that was here before me.
这意味着什么
That means something.
这意味着你在这的时间太长了
Aye. It means you've been here a long time
该轮到你拉梯子了
and it's your turn to pull up the ladder.
我们的德妮丝...
Our Denise...
跑到旅馆来责备我 她想要摆脱我
Coming to the inn to chide me. She wants rid of me.
她只怕也想把我推倒在路上
She might as well push me down the road.
她只想让你感到快乐 就这样 艾德蒙
She just wants you to be happy, that's all, Edmund.
你肯定看得出吧
Surely you can see that.
我要把我的店从头到尾漆上颜色 然后
I'll paint my shop from top to bottom. And then...
如果你想的话 我星期天可以来帮你
I can help you out if you want, on Sunday.
礼拜天是我用来向着河的上流追女孩的
I'd only spend it chasing girls up the river.
或往下流追
Or chasing girls down the river.
这里就是我所知道的世界
Everything I know in this world is right here.
"店铺出售"
我很担心凯瑟琳
I am concerned for Katherine.
她丈夫的嫉妒心已经影响到她了
Her husband's jealousy is telling on her.
我怕她可能会病倒
I fear she might fall ill.
那最好了
Well, that is all to the good.
你向她献殷勤的效果已经达...达到了
Your courting of her has w-worked to our favour.
我想向你说清楚
What I am trying to make clear to you is that
我不能继续欺骗下去了
I cannot continue with this deception.
汤姆・威斯顿是个非常危险又不稳定的人
Tom Weston is a dangerously volatile man.
他开始受压力的影响了
The pressure is telling on him.
- 我见过 - 那最好了
- I have seen it. - All to the good.
莫里先生 请容我说一句
Mr Moray, sir, if I may.
你已经演完你的角色了
You have played your part.
而且做得很棒
And played it handsomely.
现在 我们要带着我们的提议
= Now, we will approach Tom Weston
去接近汤姆・威斯顿
with our proposal.
什么提议
What proposal?
约翰?
John?
- 约翰? - 乔纳斯 带他往这走
- John? - Jonas, take him through this way.
我不想让她发现你在这
I don't want her to find you here.
先生
Sir.
你在里面吗?
Are you in there?
约翰 你在里面吗?
John, are you in there?
你在和谁说话
Who were you talking to?
我刚反应过来 我肯定是在自说自话
It has finally come to it. I must have been talking to myself.
巴伦坦? 他把他所有的钱
Ballentine? He's spending all of his money
都花在一个比他女儿还年轻的老婆上了
on a wife who's young enough to be his daughter.
这男人已经被爱冲昏头脑了
The man's mind is addled with love.
这有什么错呢
And what's wrong with that?
没有 没有错
Nothing. Nothing's wrong with that.
一旦涉及生意上的事
When it comes to business matters,
他的脑子可比我们都敏锐
his mind is as sharp as the best of us.
我相信如果去向他提议...
I believe if we came to him with a proposal...
他的漂亮新娘很喜欢我们商场 亲爱的
He has a pretty bride who's taken a fancy to the store, darling,
我们没有理由相信这男人是个合适的投资者
those are not grounds for us to believe the man is a suitable investor.
你反对这个想法是因为是我向你提出的吗?
Are you opposed to the idea because I suggested it to you?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我今天状态不佳
I'm not at my best.
你怎么这么易怒 这么心烦的样子?
Why are you so irritable, so distracted?
是因为凯瑟琳吗
Is it Katherine?
什么意思
What do you mean?
我们去吃晚饭的时候我看到她是什么样了
I saw how she was when we went to dinner.
她一句话都没说
She hardly said a word.
她已经愤怒至极了
She was festering with rage.
我觉得她的婚姻不幸福
I think she's unhappy in her marriage.
她差不多也是这么说的
She almost said as much.
你去看她了?
You went to see her?
是的 去求她拴住她的老公
Yes. Yes. To plead with her to rein in her husband.
他干涉店里的生意
His dabbling in the business of the store
已经让这儿的日子很难过了
is making life here quite impossible.
但你没告诉我你会去见凯瑟琳
But you did not tell me you were going to see Katherine.
他们是我们的上司 我们尽量必须应付他们
While they are our masters, we must deal with them, as best we can.
当心点约翰
Be careful John.
凯瑟琳可没忘记 她永远也不会忘记的
Katherine has not forgotten. She'll never forget.
你不愿意卖 我接受
You do not wish to sell. I accept that.
我们应该相互理解
We shall both of us proceed on that understanding.
但如果我没有告诉你我的想法
But it would be duplicitous of me
那我就是个两面派了
were I not to advise you of my intentions.
我兄弟和我在曼切斯特和利物浦各有一家店
My brother and I have a store in Manchester and one in Liverpool.
我们希望向南部和北...北部扩张
We wish to expand south and, indeed, n-north.
我们的目标是成为第一个
Our intention is to be the first and, sir,
也是唯一一个国际连锁商城
the only, national formation of emporiums.
你是打算建在这里吗
And you propose to build here?
我们有个施工地址 已经在起草计划了
We have a site. Plans are being drawn.
到目前为止 威斯顿先生
Up until now, Mr Weston,
只是些小商店与天堂百货之间的小打小闹
the battle has been between the small stores and The Paradise.
那种仗赢得很轻松
That war was easily won.
等我建好了
If I build
那则会发生一次完全不同规模的交锋
will be an almighty clash on an altogether different scale.
一场价格战争
A price war.
你的一些最佳员工可能会被更好的薪资所诱惑
Some of your best staff might well be tempted by better offers.
顾客会... 至少会分散
Customers will be, at the very least, divided.
为什么你提前警告我
Why would you wish to forewarn me?
这意味着我会防备 不让你得逞
It means that I might arm myself against your intentions.
因为这场战争我肯定能...能赢
It is a battle I W-WILL win.
但那肯定会用很多钱 我希望你
But it will be a costly affair. I would prefer you...
现在接受失败吗 在我自己家里?
To accept defeat now? In the comfort of my own home.
不是失败 不 应该是说个人的胜利
Not defeat, no. Perhaps a more personal triumph.
你应该赞同
You will appreciate that a businessman must be,
一个生意人是一根筋的
shall we say, "single-minded"?
如果我建好了 我想雇莫里做我的商场经理
If I build, I intend to employ Moray as my store manager
我会提供他足够的钱 只要能赢
and I will provide him with whatever funds are needed to succeed.
如果你把天堂商店卖给我
If you sell The Paradise to me,
我会把莫里解雇
I will cast Moray into the wilderness
永远驱逐他
never to return.
不
No.
我理解情感可能会战胜理智 先生
I understand that emotion might get the better of judgment, sir,
所以我给你一个礼拜
so I will wait for one week whilst you allow yourself some
让你在家好好考...考虑这件事
re-reflection on the matter.
让我解释一下
Let me explain.
你所描述的
What you describe,
芬顿先生 是些客观因素
Mr Fenton, are the circumstances.
你现在所应对的是一个男人
What you are dealing with is a man.
如果我对你的要求低头
If I surrender to your demand,
就会变成
it will be...
一个懦夫
..because I am a coward.
一旦你把名字拿下来 那就是结局了 是吗
Once you take the name down, that really is the end, isn't it?
是的
It is.
是的 你必须得做 把它拿下来
Yeah, well, you have to. Take it down.
你不能给"艾德蒙・洛维特"涂上亮丽的新色
I mean, you can't paint Edmund Lovett
再放上去了
back up there again
否则这看上去会成什么样
in bright new colours, cos what's that going to look like?
是啊 但如果我的名字不在店上
Yeah, but if my name's not above the shop,
那我是在卖什么?
what is it I'm supposed to be selling?
任何一个想买的人都会想知道
Anyone interested is going to want to know
他们要买下的一个经营发达的企业
they're buying a going concern.
- 你可以就写"服装店" - 你看吧
You could just write up there - "Draper's Shop". There, you see!
- 从孩子的口中说出来了 - 是的好吧
- Straight from the mouths of babes. - Yeah... Well...
你是来提供意见的
It's for you to have opinions.
我是来做决定的
It's for me to decide.
多加一点 谢谢
Oh, a little more, thank you.
你的花园真漂亮 露西尔
You have such a lovely garden, Lucille.
快吃 姑娘们
Eat up, girls.
你们没享受完可不许走
You're not allowed to leave until you are properly indulged.
四个女店员在一起 一个男人的影子都没有!
Four shop girls on a blanket and not a man in sight!
今天可没人会享受
No-one's going to be indulged today.
吃点肉
Have some meat.
有乡下人
There's peasant.
注: 英语中"乡下人"与"鸡肉"拼写相似
我意思说 鸡肉
I mean "pheasant".
在我家乡 "乡下人"是种美味佳肴
Where I come from, "peasant" is a delicacy.
有个蛋在最上面呢
We have it with an egg on top!
我是个乡下人
I'm a peasant.
实际上
As good as.
我知道你们都知道
I know you all know it.
我不知道怎么打扮 怎么走路 怎么说话
I don't know how to dress, how to walk, how to talk.
你们肯定很疑惑
You must be wondering
我怎么嫁得了巴伦坦这么好的丈夫!
how I got myself a husband like Ballentine!
这可不关我们事 露西尔
Well, it's none of our business, Lucille.
我想知道
I was wondering.
他病了
He was sick.
我是在看护他 然后
I was nursing him and, er...
男人们总是喜欢护士
Men always fall for the nurses.
好了 现在我们知道了 他能有你真幸运
There. Now, we know. He's a lucky man to have you.
还有"油炸杂种"和"乡下人"一起上吗?
Any fried mongrel to go with that peasant?
他生病时在医院追求你的吗?
Did he court you whilst he was sick in hospital?
我让他把我迷倒了
I let him woo me.
为什么不呢 我已经心碎很多次了
Why should I not? I've had my heart broke plenty of times.
当男人们病好了 就离开了
Men get well and they move away...
然后就忘记他们曾爱过
..and they forget they were in love.
我以为我已经没戏了
I thought my time had passed.
但巴伦坦没有忘记 他想要娶我
But Ballentine didn't forget. He wanted to marry me,
我知道这儿的夫人们都怎么看我
and I know what all the wives around here think of me.
你们肯定也这样想
You must be thinking the same.
我不过是有张漂亮脸蛋
I'm no more than a pretty face...
你和我们的唯一不同 露西尔
The only difference between you and us, Lucille,
就是你找到了一个好男人
is that you chased after a good man.
对吧 姑娘们
Isn't that right, girls?
你找到了一个丈夫
You found a husband
他唯一想做的事情就是让你开心
whose only desire is to make you happy.
如果你认为我们会因此而在这里评论你
If you think we're here to judge you for that,
那你就错了
then you're wrong.
谢谢你 谢谢你 克莱拉
Thank you. Thank you, Clara.
能向你求助真是给我很大的安慰 莫里
It truly is a comfort to me to have you to turn to, Moray.
我希望你能知道到我有多庆幸
I hope that you appreciate how grateful I am.
凯瑟琳 汤姆是在惩罚你
Katherine, Tom is punishing you
因为我在这 会使他想起
because I'm here to remind him
我们之间的一些事情
of how things were between us.
这对他来说是一种挑衅
It is a provocation to him.
如果我们见面 我觉得情况会更加糟糕
If we see one another, I can't help thinking it will make this worse.
对我诚实 并对你自己也诚实
Be honest with me, be honest with yourself.
你认为我们这样下去会让情况好起来吗?
Do you suppose it will make things better if we continue like this?
我把你带回这里就是为了惩罚你
I brought you back here to punish you.
这不足以毁掉你
It wasn't enough to ruin you.
这还远达不到你抛弃我时带来的伤痛
That could never match the hurt I felt when you abandoned me.
我把你安排在那个职位
I put you back in that place
因此我可以看着你和德妮丝
so that I could watch you with Denise and...
我不在乎会花多长时间
..I didn't care how long it might take...
我想让她尝尝我的感受
I wanted her to feel as I felt.
害怕失去你
To be terrified of losing you.
然后 再失去你
And then, to lose you.
但是 现在
But now...
和你一起呆几分钟 感受你的温柔
A few moments alone with you, to feel your tenderness,
你的庇护 我现在不想伤害任何人
your protection... I don't want to hurt anyone now.
我只是想知道以后我们还会像现在这样
I only want to know that sometimes we can be like this.
- 不要将它夺走 - 汤姆会毁了你
Don't take that away from me. Tom will destroy you...
德妮丝也会毁了你
Denise will destroy you.
你想过这个吗?
Have you thought of that?
汤姆告诉了我他在店里所看见的
Tom told me what he sees in the store.
德妮丝很有野心
Denise has such ambition.
当他提议让她去巴黎的时候
I saw her face when he suggested
我看到过她的表情
that she might go to Paris.
他说她将会超过你
He says she will outrun you...
你要我对你诚实 莫里
You asked me to be honest with you, Moray.
那我也恳求你认清事实
I implore you to meet truth with truth.
我所说的
What I describe,
你也看出来了吧?
is that what you see?
你安慰了我
You have comforted me.
我就不能安慰你吗
Can't I comfort you?
您有一个如此华丽的家 美好的生活
You have such a splendid home, a good life,
一个可爱的妻子
a lovely wife,
但是
but...
为什么我不退休呢 为什么要呢
Why do I not retire? Why should I?
曾有好几次机会我可以卖掉我的啤酒厂
Oh, I've had several opportunities to sell my brewery,
但是我从未动心
but I've never been tempted.
是工作让我一直在继续
It's what keeps me going, work.
让我一直思维敏捷
Keeps me sharp.
每一个新的挑战都要花费我十年光阴
Every new challenge takes ten years off my age!
好吧 可能是五年
Well, maybe five.
我生产啤酒 我感觉我已经竭尽所能
I make beer, and I feel I've done all I can
把麦芽酒推向全国
selling ales to the nation.
我还要再一次征战商场
I want one more business conquest
好使我再年轻起来
to make me young again.
我听说莫里想筹集资金买回他的商场
Now I hear that Moray is trying to raise funds to buy back his store
但没取得成功
without much success.
他是怎么失去它的?
How did he come to lose it?
他 坠入了爱河
He...fell in love.
他放弃了他的所有来爱这个女孩
He gave up all that he had to be true to his girl.
我听过这些故事
Aye, I've heard the stories.
这使我更喜欢他了
It rather endears him to me.
另一方面也是因为我在我的暮年变得浪漫了
But then, I have become something of a romantic in my old age,
正如你所见 德妮丝
as you can see, Denise.
巴伦坦先生 您可以见见莫里先生吗?
Mr Ballentine, might you meet with Mr Moray
好让他能给您投资天堂百货的提议
so that he might put before you a proposal to invest in The Paradise?
这是一个健全的 有广泛扩张潜力的企业
It is a sound enterprise, with potential for extensive expansion.
我们不会受时尚变化无常的影响
We are not vulnerable to the whims of fashion,
事实上 我们总是在走在顾客的前面
in fact, we are always ahead of our customers.
当时尚生产商创造新产品时
As modern manufacturing creates new goods,
我们是第一个供应给消费者的
we are the first to offer them.
越来越多的人来到这个城市
More and more people are coming to the city,
我是这样 你的妻子也是这样
as I did, as your wife did,
客人想要的是新潮的 有魅力的
and what they want is the new, the glamorous,
外国货
foreign goods.
人们想要改变 天堂百货就是一个天堂
People want betterment, and The Paradise is a haven
他们想要这里都有
for all that they wish for.
既然你做得这么好
Why would I want Moray
为什么会想让莫里来给我提议呢?
to present to me when you do it so admirably?
对不起 我太得意忘形了
Oh! I'm sorry, I got carried away...
不要对你所擅长的东西说抱歉
Nae, don't apologise for what you're good at.
我想要一个儿子
I wanted a son.
一个能继承我的生意的儿子
Someone who would take on my business
然后在他那一代使其繁荣
and make it flourish for his own generation.
如果我真有这样一个儿子
If I'd had the son I'd wished for,
他肯定就像你一样 德妮丝
he'd have been just like you, Denise.
现在 你写一份正式的提案
Now, you put together a formal proposition
我会好好考虑的
and I'll consider it.
艾德蒙 不得不这么说 你做得真不错
It's a fine job you're doing, Edmund. It has to be said.
对啊 你知道接下来会怎么样
Yes, so fine you know what's coming,
对吧 梅尔托?
don't you, Myrtle?
确实 当他完成外面的后
I do. When he's finished the outside,
他又会想把里面弄一遍
it'll cross his mind to do the inside.
所以里外都会变成一样
Just so they're all the same, like.
当他完成里面后
And when he's done the inside...
他会后退一步欣赏他的作品 然后说
He'll step back and admire his handiwork and say...
当我把它弄得如此辉煌后
"Seems a shame to leave the place
再离开这个地方似乎是一件憾事
when I've got it looking so splendid!"
来吧 艾德蒙 吃蛋糕吧
Come on, Edmund, eat your cake.
艾德蒙 来吧 吃蛋糕了 艾德蒙
Edmund? Come on, eat your cake. Edmund...?
莫里 德妮丝可能正好找到你所要找的东西了
Moray, Denise may well have found exactly what you are looking for.
巴伦坦先生说好愿意投资
Mr Ballentine as good as said he's willing to invest.
他想让你见见他
He'd like you to meet with him.
凯瑟琳和汤姆不想卖
Katherine and Tom are not minded to sell.
如果他们认为我们在对他们玩花样
It would antagonise them if they thought
说不定会反击的
we were manoeuvring against them.
当然有资金投入是没有坏处的
Surely there's no harm in having the funding in place?
我们必须找最优的投资
We must find investment that is from the best source
同时也得在最合适的时机
that comes at the most favourable time.
莫里先生 你的信件
Mr Moray, sir, your messages.
我知道 先生 达德利先生会处理
I know, sir. Mr Dudley will deal with them.
我真渴望回到我们天真无邪的时候
I long to go back to that time of innocence between us.
我们两个在夜里说着悄悄话
The two of us just talking in the dark.
亲爱的 我们从来没有天真无邪的时候
Sweetheart, it was never innocent.
你当时定了婚 而我是为你工作的售货员
You were engaged to be married, and I was a shop girl working for you.
重重困难摆在我们面前
Things have always been difficult,
可我们坚持下来了 因为我们爱着彼此
but we persevered because we love one another.
现在也是这样
It's the same now.
有时候 我多希望你没有在这工作
Sometimes, I wish you just didn't work here.
我希望我们在街上邂逅
I wish we'd met in the street.
我只想我们能够爱着对方
I just want us to be able to love one another
一切只要简简单单就好 这有什么问题呢
and for it all to be simple. What is wrong with that?
这没有问题
There's nothing wrong with that.
我认为这叫做浪漫
I think they call it romance.
你认为我们要和莫里对着干吗?
You think we should defy Moray?
不要那样说
Let's not call it that.
应该说是帮助 只是没让他知道 或者同意
Let's call it helping. Without his knowledge. Or consent.
但是尽管是帮助 如果我们能弄到可行的资金
But helping nonetheless. If we can secure workable funds...
威斯顿夫妇在逼约翰 达德利
The Westons are crushing John, Dudley.
我们应该要做一些事情 即使只是
We have to do something. Even if it only amounts
给他一点点继续下去的希望
to giving him a little bit of hope to carry on.
我不确定私底下行动是最好的方式 德妮丝
I'm not sure that acting secretly is the best way, Denise.
我不知道梅尔托在她的糕点里放了什么
I don't know what Myrtle puts in her pastry,
她说她有一种秘制调料
she says she has a secret ingredient.
只要不是她的脚趾甲
Provided it's not her toenails,
如果尝起来还不错 我就不需要知道
I don't need to know as long as it tastes good.
噢 德妮丝 你叔叔今天吃了什么?
Eh, Denise, what is eating up your uncle?
他甚至都不吃我的蛋糕
I couldn't even get him to eat my cake today.
我必须去对面看看他 我一直很忙
I must go across and see him, I've been so busy.
或许他已知道你在蛋糕里放了什么 梅尔托
Perhaps he's wise to what you put in your recipe, Myrtle.
我知道当我和巴伦坦在一起的时候人们在看我
I see people looking at me when I'm with Ballentine.
当我把他带进商场时我看到你也有同样的神情
I saw it on your face when I brought him into the store.
为什么要在意别人怎么看你呢?
What does it matter what others think of you?
因为那是真的啊
Because it's true.
一定是真的
It must be true.
他对我越好我越内疚
The more kindness he shows to me, the more guilty I feel.
我做错了 我不得不承认 我得承认
I made a mistake. I have to admit it, I have to.
我要离开他
I will leave him.
这样对待一个爱你的男人不是很残忍么?
Isn't that a cruel thing to do to a man who loves you?
我留下更是对他的残忍
It's more cruel if I stay.
凯瑟琳?
Katherine?
不要不懂装懂
Don't pretend to know or understand anything you don't.
他有那么多年的从商经验 他会看出来的
He's a businessman of many years' experience. He will know.
把数据弄得简单些 别抬高夸大
Keep the figures simple - don't inflate or exaggerate.
如果被他发现 你就会失去他
If he catches you out, then you've lost him.
如果你跟我一块去不会更好吗?
Wouldn't it be better if you came with me?
不 不会的
No, it wouldn't.
为什么?
But, why wouldn't it?
因为是你找到巴伦坦的啊 他是你的战利品
Because you found Ballentine, he's your conquest.
没有人
There's no-one here.
达德利先生 你刚说的不是真的原因吧?
What you just told me, Mr Dudley, that's not the true reason, is it?
我去呢 会给他展示数据 他也会觉得我
I would present Mr Ballentine with figures, and he would see in me
是个信得过的合作者 而你去呢?
a man who could be trusted with his investment. You?
德妮丝 你的风采能照亮整个洽谈室
You would light up the room, Denise.
我擅长我正在做的 也能把它做得最好
I'm good at what I do. The best at my own job.
但像这种事就需要个企业家来完成了
But something like this takes an entrepreneur.
我只想看看当我告诉约翰我们有出路时
I just want to see the look on John's face when I tell him
他的表情
we have a way out.
你会看到的 德妮丝 你会的
And you will, Denise. You will.
走吧 该走了
Go on, go.
去睡觉 祝你好运
Go to bed. And good luck.
出发咯
Walk on!
德妮丝...
Denise...
先生 威斯顿先生在军队时发生了点事
There is something about Mr Weston's time in the army, sir.
一些他无法提起的事
Something he cannot bear to speak about.
德妮丝刚坐马车走了 她去哪了?
Denise has just left the street in a carriage. Where has she gone?
先生 您最好还是问达德利先生吧
You might be better asking Mr Dudley about that, sir.
克莱拉? 克莱拉?
Clara? Clara?
我不知道我在想什么
I don't know what possessed me
而跟你说了关于我丈夫的那些事
to say such things to you about my husband.
我睡不着觉担心...
I couldn't sleep for fear that...
你没把我说的话告诉给别人吧 有吗?
You didn't tell anyone what I said to you, did you?
没什么可以告诉别人的
There was nothing to tell.
我会受不了的 如果巴伦坦知道了
I couldn't bear it if Ballentine found out.
知道了我对你说的那些
I mean, found out what I'd been saying.
可你不是心意已决么?
But your mind is made up?
噢! 我还没见过这些披肩呢
Oooh! I've not seen these shawls before.
你喜欢吗? 克莱拉 我们都得有一条
Do you like them? We must both have one, Clara.
没必要这么做巴伦坦太太
There's no need for that, Mrs Ballentine.
我只想让你知道你对我有多重要
I just want to show you what you mean to me.
我有朋友了
I have a friend.
我有真正的朋友了
I have a true friend.
我希望你收下它
I want you to have this.
我不能收的
I can't accept that from you.
好嘛 你一定要收下 这代表你是我的
Please. You must. To show you.
朋友 我信赖的朋友
Friends. Trusted friends.
商场有相关的规定的
There are rules about such things in the store.
如果我收了 我会丢了工作的
If I accept that, I could lose my position.
不要告诉他们啊 就我俩知道
Then don't tell them. Be between us.
你觉得你能买到我的同情? 我的沉默?
Do you think you can buy my sympathy, my silence?
我的友情?
Buy my friendship?
你只是我的客人
You're a customer.
除此之外我们没别的关系
You are no more to me than that.
芙罗拉?
Flora?
明年的预期收入...
The projected income for the next year...
是的 先生?
Yes, sir?
我以为会多一点的 是出了什么问题吗?
I imagined it might be more. Is there a problem?
我是有点太谨慎了
I have erred on the side of caution.
但错误的期望会导致失望的
False expectations create disappointment
也会有失败感
and a sense of failure.
我预计的和我们做到的
What I have predicted and what we reach for
是两回事
are not the same thing.
那德妮丝你有你们能做到的预期收入么?
And do you have figures for what you might reach for, Denise?
为什么莫里不亲自来介绍呢?
Why did Moray not make this presentation himself?
先生请您原谅他这个小疏忽
Please, don't hold this one small omission against him, sir.
莫里白手起家 创立天堂百货
Moray has built The Paradise from nothing.
他比所有人都清楚怎么经营好这间百货
He knows better than anyone how to make the store a success.
德妮丝 我很满意你提的方案
Your proposal meets with my satisfaction, Denise.
但我还有一些其它因素要考虑
But I have other considerations to take into account.
我会很快答复你的
I will not keep you waiting too long for an answer.
谢谢你 先生
Thank you, sir.
他是个幸运的家伙
He's a very fortunate fellow.
希望他知道
I hope he knows it.
我看到她坐在我的凳子上...
I found her sitting in my chair...
就像她在试宝座似的
As though she were trying out the throne.
你以为我没做过这事么? 还有山姆
Do you suppose I haven't done the same? And Sam?
我上次还看到亚瑟坐在上面呢
I once found Arthur sitting there.
莫里 每个人都有权利做白日梦的
We're all allowed to daydream, Moray.
又不会有什么坏处
There's no harm in it.
抱歉 好像是我自己在钻牛角尖 是吧?
I'm sorry, I seem to be jumping at shadows, don't I?
你知道为什么吗?
You know why?
因为你被和乔纳斯和芬顿的勾当蒙蔽了
You're consumed with such underhand business
你甚至已经看不到
with Jonas and Fenton that you refuse to notice
巴伦坦是你最好的投资人 究竟为什么啊?
that Ballentine's the perfect financier for you. Why is that?
因为是... 德妮丝找到他的
Because Denise...found him.
是她争取到的
She wooed him.
这是她为你准备的礼物啊!
She brought you a gift!
她这么做是为了你啊!
She did it for you!
因为她爱你
Because she loves you.
你看不见真正重要的东西
You've lost sight of what really matters.
你反倒宁愿去跟凯瑟琳・威斯顿混在一起
Instead you prefer to dally with Katherine Weston
希望能...
in the hope that you can...
谁知道你想干嘛
who knows what.
达德利 我成大傻瓜了
I've been an almighty fool, Dudley.
的确 那你现在想怎么补救?s
You have. And what do you propose to do about it?
凯瑟琳 我去你房间不是去吓你的
I did not come to your room to frighten you, Katherine.
我只想去看看你
I came to look at you.
我接受出售天堂百货的提议了
I've received an offer to sell The Paradise.
你怎么会愿意的呢?
Why would you want to do such a thing?
因为这样是最好的
I've decided it is for the best.
不 你不能这么做
No. You can't.
我可以 我是你的丈夫
I can. I'm your husband.
我的决定说了算
What I decide will prevail.
但这不合理啊...
But it makes no sense...
凯瑟琳 我昨晚去你房间是想告诉你...
Last night, Katherine, I came to your room to tell you...
我不想失去你
I don't want to lose you.
如果我们能停止会怎么样?
What if we were to stop?
停止...
Stop...
折磨彼此
punishing one another.
如果我们能说...
What if we were to say...
我们结婚了
we are married now.
我们能好好地一块生活
We can make a life.
芙罗拉爱你
Flora adores you.
我们有个孩子要照顾
We have a child to care for.
我答应你 我永远都在这
I promise you, I will always be here.
绝不食言
I will not break my word.
'我亲爱的莫里
'My dear Moray.
我不得不再一次利用
I must put upon your good nature
你的好脾气和善良 请求你
and your kindness towards me once more, and ask that you
马上过来见我'
come to meet with me urgently.'
'请原谅我的匆忙 看到你时我会向你解释的
'Please forgive my haste, I will explain when I see you.
凯瑟琳'
Katherine.'
约翰?
John?
你出去么?
Are you going out?
亲爱的 我约了坎贝尔・巴伦坦
Darling, I have an appointment to see Campbell Ballentine.
- 我听你的话去找他 - 太棒了
- I took your advice and approached him. - That's wonderful.
我太开心了
I'm so pleased.
- 你是克莱拉 没错吧? - 没错 先生
- It's Clara, isn't it? - It is, sir.
抱歉 失陪了
If you'll excuse me.
克莱拉我有点事跟你说
I'd like a word with you, Clara.
你告诉他了吗?
Did you tell him?
我才不会说呢
I wouldn't do such a thing.
你说了 我看到了
You did. I saw you.
我看到你和我的丈夫在聊天
I saw you speaking with my husband.
他是在邀请我
He was inviting me,
邀请所有的女孩去他的生日派对
inviting all of the girls, to his birthday party,
来取悦你
to please YOU.
就是这个!你明白了吧!
There! Do you see now?
你明白我必须要离开他的理由了吧?
Do you see now why I must leave him?
明白什么啊?
WHAT is there to see?
我配不上这样一个好男人
I don't deserve a man like him.
他对我的爱越深
The more devoted he is to me,
他就越难发现我真正的样子
the more I wait for the day when he sees me as I truly am.
我骗了他 我魅惑了他
I tricked him. I bewitched him.
你是什么意思?
What do you mean?
当我照顾他的时候 有一天晚上...
When I was nursing him, there was one night...
他看起来那么的英俊 他睡着的时候...
He looked so handsome, when he was sleeping and...
我情不自禁地...
...I couldn't seem to stop myself.
我吻了他
I kissed him.
我感觉他的灵魂在睡梦中被我偷走了
I feel like I've stolen his soul in his sleep
这就是他爱我的原因
and that's why he loves me.
你为什么要用这种迷信来折磨自己呢?
Why would you torment yourself with such superstition?
您真的认为他这么容易被瞒骗吗?
Do you really think he's so easily fooled?
你没有偷走他的爱 也没有欺骗他
You did not steal his love, you did not trick him.
请听我说
Look, listen to me.
- 你爱他吗? - 当然!
- Do you love him? - Of course!
那就好好爱他
Then LOVE him.
那就是他所期望的全部
That's all he wants from you.
真心爱他 你就能摆脱你的心魔
Love him and you'll be rid of your torments.
如果你离开了他
If you leave him,
你就会在余生中不断地诅咒自己
you will curse yourself for the rest of your days.
让那些别人的看法见鬼去吧
To hell with what other people think of you.
你的丈夫真心爱慕你
Your husband adores you.
拥有这样一位爱人你很幸运
You've been lucky in finding such a man.
为什么不去接受这份幸运呢?
Why not just accept your luck?
好 谢谢你
Yes, thank you.
为什么如此吃惊呢 德妮丝
Don't look so startled, Denise.
我以为你见到我会很开心
I thought you'd be pleased to see me.
是很开心 巴伦坦先生 只是...
I am, Mr Ballentine. It's just...
很高兴见到您
I am glad to see you.
我本希望莫里至少能够
I had hoped that Moray would have the good grace
爽快的给我个信儿
to send me a note at least.
他还没有联系您吗?
He's made no contact with you?
不过这也无妨
Perhaps that is just as well.
我被这个地方迷住了 德妮丝
I am tempted by this place, Denise.
我想投资
I want to invest.
这个消息真是太棒了 谢谢您
Well, that is wonderful news. Thank you.
但是同时我也考虑了另外的可能...
But one of the things I've had to consider is this...
不如我买下整个商店 安排一位经理
I could just as well buy the store. Put in a manager.
一个我可以信任 可以寄予希望的人
Someone I could trust, someone I have faith in.
一个有远见 抱负的...
Someone with vision, ambition...
先生 我恳请您在做出任何这样的考量之前
Please, sir, before any such considerations,
和莫里见一次面
I implore you to meet with Moray,
听听他对于这个地方的看法
hear him talk about this place.
我敢肯定 您会想要和他做生意
I am certain you'll want to do business with him.
好的
Very well.
这件事上我相信你的判断力 德妮丝
I will trust your judgment in this, Denise.
谢谢您 先生!
Thank you, sir!
还有...
And...
谢谢您
Thank you.
你可以转行啦 艾德蒙
You could take on a new calling, Edmund.
我的房子也得好好刷一刷!
My house needs painting!
我知道我不能永远呆在这儿
I know I can't stay here.
我知道我已经结婚了
I know I'm a married man.
我有了全新的生活 我知道
I have a new life. I know it.
我觉得我过去的生活被带走了
I feel like my old life's been taken away from me.
被硬生生地夺走了
I've been robbed of it.
我无法放手
I can't let it go.
还不行
Not yet.
不能就这样
Not like this.
艾德蒙!
Edmund!
艾德蒙 怎么了? 慢点 慢点! 艾德蒙!
Edmund, what's wrong? Easy, easy! Edmund!
你还好吗?
You all right?
艾德蒙!
Edmund!
叔叔!
Uncle!
艾德蒙 快去!
Edmund. Go!
叔叔!
Uncle!
帮忙啊!
Get help!
艾德蒙叔叔? 我是德妮丝!
Uncle Edmund? It's Denise!
他会好起来的
He will recover from this.
他需要休息 长时间的休息
He'll need rest. A lifetime of rest.
他对我就像是父亲一样
He's been like a father to me.
我只顾着忙我自己的事情 都没有时间陪他
I was so caught up in my own concerns, I had no time for him.
最后一次和他说话的时候 我还在责备他
The last time I spoke to him, I was chiding him.
那下次你再和他说话的时候
Then next time you speak to him,
一定要让他开心地笑
be sure to make him laugh.
约翰在哪里?
Where's John?
要是他知道发生了什么
If he knew what had happened,
他肯定会想要来陪着你
I am certain he would want to be with you here.
你没有回答我的问题 达德利
You haven't answered my question, Dudley.
他在哪儿?
Where is he?
感谢你的到来
Thank you for coming.
- 凯瑟琳... - 能否让我说呢?
- Katherine... - Will you allow me to speak
我已经想明白了 而且也下定决心了
while it is all clear to me and I have the resolve?
我现在是一位母亲了
I am a mother now.
我要对我的孩子负责
I have the responsibility of a child.
我忍不住要去想象我的行为
I can't bear to think that my actions
可能会让我的亲爱的女儿感到恐惧
might cause fear for that dear girl.
你明白了吗?
Do you see?
我必须阻止自己再和你单独见面了
I must forbid myself from seeing you alone.
是的
Yes.
是的 我明白
Yes, I see.
这是最后一次了
This must be the last time.
那我不希望再让你背负更多的不安了 凯瑟琳
Then I would not want to burden you with any more anxiety, Katherine.
- 我会离开的... - 要不...
- I will go... - Perhaps...
...再坐一会儿吧
...a few moments more.
当我独自一人时 我的思绪被理性主宰
When I am alone my thoughts are governed by reason.
但是和你在一起时 一切就不同了
But when I am with you, it is different.
我被想要见到你想要触碰你手的念头给征服了
I am overcome with the wish just to look at you, to touch your hand.
我说过 我希望你在痛苦的时候能来找我
I said I wanted you to come to me in your distress.
我对你的关心 凯瑟琳 一直是非常真诚的
My concern for you, Katherine, has been entirely genuine.
我希望你能了解
I want you to know that.
- 我今天来是... - 不!
- When I came here today... - No!
我爱德妮丝
I love Denise.
我不能以任何的...
I cannot in any way...
你一直都钟情于她吗?
You were always true to her?
是的 全心全意
With all my heart, yes.
我要自己站起来
I will stand on my own.
凯瑟琳?
Katherine?
是不是他害你这样的?
Did HE do this to you?
我不能控制自己
I can't help myself.
德妮丝...
Denise...
对不起 我没能陪着你
I'm sorry I wasn't here with you.
你刚才和凯瑟琳在一起 对不对?
You were with Katherine, weren't you?
看着我 告诉我你去哪了?
Look at me and tell me where you've been.
我...
I've...
我是和凯瑟琳在一起
I've been with Katherine.
但我没有背叛你
I've not betrayed you.
我想和我叔叔独处
I wish to be alone with my uncle.
求你了 让我在叔叔身边安静地坐一会儿
Please, let me sit in peace with my uncle.
这真是太棒了
It really is. It's wonderful.
- 都满意吗? - 都满意
- All is well? - All is well.
我觉得是时候退休了 是不是?
I think it's about time I retired, isn't it?
我不会责备您的 如果这就是您想要的
I am not going to chide you, if that's what you want.
我只想喝一杯茶
What I want is a cup of tea.
您一直说我泡的茶是世界上最难喝的
You always said I make the worst tea in the world.
那就来一杯世界上最难喝的茶吧
Then I want a cup of the worst tea in the world.
为什么只有痛苦才能教会我们珍惜所拥有的?
Why is it that pain has to teach us what is right under our noses?
我爱慕奥德丽整整二十三年
23 years I've loved Audrey,
没想到有美梦成真的一天
never believing it would be.
现在她为我守候 而我却为了维护一点自尊心
Now, she's waiting for me and I fight it
而抗拒这件事情
to hold on to a bit of pride.
好吧...
Well...
我不会再抗拒了 德妮丝
I'm done fighting now, Denise.
德妮丝 我希望你不要...
Denise, I don't want you to...
我知道这一定...
I know this must be...
请你一定不要走
You must not think of leaving.
我不会走的 我属于这里
I am not going to leave. I belong here.
我想要向你们介绍一位非常特殊的客人
I'd like to introduce you all to someone very special.
这个国家最具盛名的摄影师之一
One of the most celebrated photographers in all of the land.
你看上去糟糕透了
You look like hell.
注: hell也指地狱
我觉得我正往地狱走呢
One feels that's exactly where I'm headed.
我们的关系只不过是一个痛苦的故事的结语
Our case was nothing more than an epilogue to an arduous tale.
- 我见过鬼 - 那只是你的幻想
- I've seen things. - You've imagined things.
哦 有鬼!
Oh, it is!
这儿有鬼啊!
It's here!